

+49 151 670 21847 - cell edgar.quezada@gmail.com
Berlin, Germany
(open for remote work)





Full-Stack Developer with a background in legal with over 20 years of experience working with teams and stakeholders. Extensive experience with electronic discovery and electronic file management teams to improve and streamline digitization of documents. Able to efficiently translate creative ideas into stable and high-performing web applications through strong analytical and creative skills. Proficient with writing clear, concise, and effective web development code using current best practices.

#### **DEVELOPMENT SKILLS**

#### Front End:

- Website building using HTML, CSS, JS, and Ruby
- Code linting & accessibility testing
- Libraries (jQuery, NodeJs, Redux)/Frameworks(Bootstrap, Vue.Js)
- Responsive design, modals, and touch interactions
- Test & Behavior Driven Development: unit testing (Jest), integration testing (Cucumber), acceptance testing, and end-to-end testing(Puppeteer)
- Continuous integration/delivery
- Functional & Object oriented programming
- Mobile Applications using React Native, Expo, PWA

# Back End:

- Node.js & Express
- APIs (JSON, RESTful, Postman)
- Hosting & Web Services (AWS, Google Firestore, Netlify, Heroku, GitHub Pages)
- Relational and non-relational databases (PostgreSQL, MongoDB)
- JWT Authentication and Authorization with Password middleware

#### Other Dev Tools:

- Git (Version control) and GitHub
- Chrome Dev Tools
- Android Studio
- Trello, Slack, Zoom, Meet and Skype
- Sublime, Atom, and Visual Studio Code

### **EDUCATION**

- Learning Golang <u>Udemy.com</u> (03/2024 - 05/2024)
- Learn to Code with Ruby Udemy.com (01/2024 - 03/2024)
- Full-Stack Web Developer - <u>CareerFoundry</u>, Berlin (10/2022 -11/2023)
- **Juris Doctor** GGU School of Law, San Francisco (08/2010 -05/2013)

#### **LANGUAGES**

Native: English, SpanishC1 level: German, ItalianA2 level: Catalan

# **SAMPLE FULL-STACK PROJECTS**

**myFlix**, Web App, CareerFoundry study project — **05/2023 - 07/2023** 

- Created a non-relational database (MongoDB) sampling movies from personal collection and user data. Database includes movie description, director information, classification, and release date;
- Built a REST API with Node.js and Express using Mongoose to allow users to interact with the database;
- Tested API endpoints using Postman, while also writing clean and concise documentation for the app, and ultimately deploying the application via Netlify.

#### **ChatApp,** PWA, CareerFoundry study project — **07/2023 - 09/2023**

- Developed a progressive web application (responsive, cross-platform, offline available) using React to display a list/chart of events from Google calendar;
- Followed test-driven-development approach, translating user-stories into scenarios for unit and integration testing (Jest), acceptance testing (Cucumber), and end-to-end testing (Puppeteer).

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Full Stack Developer, twrk, Inc., Moreno Valley, CA — 06/2024 - Present

• Involved in building, testing, and deploying TWRK tools using modern software technologies which will revolutionize the job search process in the United States.

#### Full Stack Developer, Quote Machine, Cape Cod, MA — 06/2024 - Present

Helped to design the relational database schema, build and maintain the API and
write the code for the standalone movie files, as well as build shell scripts for
background processes such as automated database backups and statistics
reports. HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Node.Js, MySQL, JSON, Git and GitHub, shell
scripting, prompt engineering for rapid deployment with AI assistance.

#### Spanish Teacher, Renée Sintenis Schule, Berlin, DE — 11/2023 - Present

• Prepare and use engaging and interactive learning materials for grade levels 1-6, while also acting as liaison for the international community to help bridge cultural and linguistic gaps.

# **Legal Advisor**, ReviverMX, San Francisco, CA — **06/2013 - 06/2020**

- Drafted, prepared, and filed corporate filings for tech-startup company with multiple stakeholders requiring daily updates;
- Advised founders about corporate structuring to improve internal operations and limit shareholder liability;
- Managed and negotiated early resolution of legal disputes with former personnel and vendors in different time zones resulting in favorable and expedient resolution.

## **Associate Attorney,** Hanna Brophy, Oakland, CA — **06/2015 - 09/2018**

- Managed 150+ disputed claim files simultaneously requiring almost daily communications with clients and opposing counsel for expedient resolution of claims;
- Trained claim adjusters to provide best resolution of legal claims to mitigate liability and/or settle cases before trial stage.

## **Law Clerk,** Offices of M. Randle, San Francisco, CA — **06/2013 - 05/2015**

 Assisted with electronic file management, client communications, drafting pleadings and discovery requests/responses for solo-practitioner with 50+ actively litigated cases.